Coffee, coffee, buzz, buzz, buzz. This
ice cream's got enough caffeine in it to
film a YouTube intro in one take. This
was a Ben & Jerry's flavor. Haven't seen
it for years. Probably don't make it
anymore. Apparently, it's still
available in the US, but I haven't seen
it anywhere else in years. It's loaded
with caffeine. I mean, not as much as
I'm going to make it. But there's this
pretty strong coffee flavor with coffee
chocolate fudge. I'm sure they would
have called it chocolate tea fudge
because, you know, things. So today I'm
going to make a new version of coffee
coffee buzz buzz buzz in the ninja
creamy ninja creamy deluxe 750 gilll
batch size. So scale it to suit your
needs. So let's get on with this. This
is super easy.
So, for this ice cream, you are going to
need
190 gram of whole milk, 255 gram of
cream, 120 g of espresso, 130 g of
sugar, 10 g of corn syrup, glucose or
golden syrup, 45 g of skim milk powder.
For the fudge that goes in this, you are
going to need 400 grams or an entire can
of condensed milk or sweetened condensed
milk if that's what it's called where
you're from. 200 g of dark chocolate and
20 g of instant coffee. Or if you have
coffee extract, you can use 10 g of
that. So, pretty easy. Ninja creamy.
We're going to get it all in. Going to
make this cold processed. The fact that
there's hot coffee in there. But that
aside, let's just get everything going.
We're going to do it in this
jug today and then pour it in the tub.
Let's start. Let's get our milk in here,
which is 190 g.
That was close. In goes our cream. 255
g. We're going to weigh out our sugar,
which is 130 g. We're going to put this
in a container because adding that
stabilizer to it. Straight into the
sugar, we're going to add 45 g of skim
milk powder. And into this mug
specifically,
120 gram of espresso. If you don't have
espresso machine, you use a pod machine
on espresso. If you don't have that, you
can use any means that you like to make
strong coffee. If you only have instant
coffee, then make strong instant coffee.
You know, like four or five teaspoons
worth of instant coffee in 120 ml of
water. So, I'm going to do espresso.
Let's get that.
continually.
>> There is our coffee. We're going to put
that in
to there.
Into that, we're going to add our 10 g.
I'm going to use corn syrup because I've
got it in the cupboard.
The 10 g of corn syrup, glucose, golden
syrup, etc., etc. Changes the texture
slightly. Counteracts the ability of the
sugar to crystallize. Um, so it's just a
really nice way of balancing out that
kind of texture. So, that's going in
there. and stabilizer into let's get rid
of this stabilizer into our sugar.
I'm going to use gu
cuz I don't want this to become icy at
all and coffee has a habit of doing
that. So 1.5 g a little bit more than we
would normally add but not too much more
because we don't want this to go gummy.
So stir those bits together. We'll put
it all over the counter. Pour that into
there. Stir it together. We're going to
dissolve those sugars. And let's pour it
into our container. Let's get rid of
some of those there. Big air bubbles cuz
we don't want those to freeze on top.
Make it look a bit weird. I might just
scoop them off.
Get rid of those.
But that is now going to go in the
freezer. Let's make the fudge. The fudge
is super easy to make. We're going to
take a can of condensed milk or
sweetened condensed milk if that's what
it's called where you're from. I said
that earlier. In Europe, this is just
called condensed milk.
And then you have evaporated milk, which
is always comes in a larger can. Um, but
it doesn't have the sugar in it. It just
has the concentrated
lactose that comes with reducing
milk. But sweetened condensed milk is
basically evaporated milk that is
condensed more and has a ton of sugar
added to it. And that's what we need.
Okay.
So, there's that. We're going to add in
to there
200 g of dark chocolate. Maybe not that.
I'm using lint chocolate cuz I use that
on the other channel. And coffee,
powdered coffee. You can't use liquid
coffee in in the fudge. So, you need to
get a powdered coffee. Whatever. It
doesn't matter cuz you're not getting
the refined taste of actually drinking
this. You're just getting that punch of
coffee to go into this fudge. So, we're
going to add in a really good two,
three, maybe even four teaspoons.
I like strong coffee. That is now going
to go on hold. We're going to melt all
of it until it's a homogeneous mix.
Gloriously glossy coffee fudge. And then
we'll pour it into a baking pan and let
it go off.
>> 5 minutes later.
>> With our fudge heated up, we're going to
get this straight into a lined pan,
baking sheet, whatever you have to hand
is fine. Just to make sure you don't
burn that chocolate. So, you're just
heating that up to
warm that condensed milk enough so that
it melts the chocolate
and
also that coffee. You're not going to
melt all those coffee granules and
that's the point to have pieces of
coffee in this fudge. It's delicious.
So,
there's that. We're going to let this
cool down
to room temperature and then we can fold
that over there and get this in the
freezer to harden off until tomorrow.
Right. Coffee. Coffee. Buzz buzz buzz in
the ninja creamy.
Let's get this spun up.
And while the ice cream is spinning,
take your fudge out of the fridge or the
freezer, wherever it is, chop it up into
little cubes. We're about to put it in
and spin it up on the mixing setting. I
think this fudge is going to cope with
the addin
setting cuz it's pretty, you know, kind
of dense, sticky, too. So, I'm going to
put some in and just see what happens.
There must be some addin that the Ninja
Creamy can absolutely cope with doing
without it needing to be hand turned in.
Maybe this is it.
All that time just to stir [snorts]
something. Let's see. Let's see how we
got on.
There we go. Coffee coffee buzz buzz
buzz Ben & Jerry's flavor done in the
Ninja Creamy. And it kind of did work
actually as using the mixing setting in
the ice cream. So that's good.
Super strong coffee flavor. Love it.
Lovely smooth ice cream. The ice cream
has got kind of like an average coffee
flavor to it. So it's not super super
strong. The fudge is loaded with coffee.
This would be delicious if you made this
in your churn machine. Obviously you'll
get that that overrun so you get a
better ultimate texture than you do in a
Ninja Creamy. I loved this ice cream
when I first did it and I love it just
as much now. I'm going to eat the rest
of this and be absolutely bouncing off
the walls. Thanks very much for
watching. Don't forget to like and
subscribe. I'll see you next week.